tkmaxx.com 2014-06-28

# Privacy Notice - TK Maxx

**Last updated: 18th March 2014**

Whenever you shop or make an enquiry with us, you may share personal information with us. This Privacy and Cookie Policy (referred to in this document as the “Policy”) sets out how we collect this information and what we do to make sure it is safe in our hands. TK Maxx and HomeSense are trading names of TJX UK, a company incorporated and registered in England and Wales with company registration number 03094828 and registered address at 50 Clarendon Road, Watford WD17 1TX. For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998, TJX UK is the data controller of any personal information you provide to us.

This Policy is the most up to date statement of our policy on privacy and cookies and takes precedence over any other statement on this site or in store. We will always indicate at the top of the Policy when it was last updated.

If there are links to third party websites on our site, these will not be covered by this Policy and we strongly recommend you refer to the terms and conditions and privacy policy on the third party website.

If you have any questions or concerns about the Policy or about the security of your personal information, please do not hesitate to contact us at [data_protection@tjxeurope.com](mailto:data_protection@tjxeurope.com). 

## When do we collect personal information?

  * When you use our website to view or buy products, evouchers or gift cards
  * When you go into our stores and are captured on CCTV which we use for purposes of health and safety and for the prevention and detection of crime.
  * When you buy products in our stores
  * When you return something
  * When you apply for a job
  * When you enter a promotion or competition
  * When you take part in customer research
  * When you agree to go on our mailing list
  * When you contact us with a comment, question or complaint or respond to a message that we send to you.
  * When you contribute content about yourself to our website, whether by direct upload, posting such content to one of our social media pages or by using a hashtag or other identifier that we use to integrate social media content with our website.

**Note**  
If you are 16 or under you may browse our website but you may not register with us or make a purchase. We do not knowingly collect personal information from any person under the age of 16 and all our promotions have a minimum age of at least 16. Our stores may ask for proof of age if an item with an age restriction is purchased and it is unclear to the associate that you are over the applicable age.

## What information do we collect about you and how do we use it?

The sort of information we collect depends on what you need us to do for you, or how much information we need to identify who you are and resolve your query. This may include: 

  * Your name and address so we can make sure an online order reaches you. 
  * Your email address so we can set up an online account for you, send you important information relating to your order and send you marketing emails if you ask us to (click here to see how you can request marketing emails or ask us not to send them). 
  * Your card details so we can take payment or make a refund whether online or in store ([click here](http://www.tkmaxx.com/customer-service/faqs/page/faqs#payment4) to see how we protect financial information). 
  * Your telephone number so we can contact you if there is a problem with delivery. 
  * Your IP address so we can, where you have consented, use appropriate cookies to enhance your visits to our website (click here to see how we use Cookies). 
  * Your signature and other appropriate information when you bring a return to our store to acknowledge receipt of the refund and help us guard against theft and fraud. 
  * Other personal details such as date of birth, gender and shopping habits appropriate to a specific promotion or competition. 
  * Footage of you that is captured on CCTV when you are on our premises. We use CCTV for the purposes of health and safety and for the prevention and detection of crime. 
  * Your contact details if you enter a competition. Your signature and other appropriate information when you bring a return to our store to acknowledge receipt of the refund and help us guard against theft and fraud. 
  * Your name, contact details and card details upon purchase of a product online to validate this information against third party databases for purposes of fraud prevention.
  * Your image and any personal information that you include in content that you contribute to the website (such as comments, photos and videos) as well as the name of the social media account from which you contribute that information.  We use this information to display your content on the website and on our social media pages and to contact you about using your content other than on the website.  We may from time to time, include this information in our adverts and other marketing campaigns but will obtain your consent before doing so.

In addition we might use the personal information you provide for our internal purposes, for example, website administration, analysis, reporting and compliance purposes or to improve merchandise selections, enhance customer service or invite you to get involved in customer research.

## How do we protect your personal information?

We maintain appropriate administrative, technical and physical security safeguards to protect against loss, misuse or unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration or destruction of the personal information you provide on our website, in our stores and through other means. However, we cannot guaranty the effectiveness of these safeguards, and nothing in this notice shall be construed as an express or implied warranty against loss, misuse or unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.

## How can you get access to any information we have about you?

You may request a copy of the personal information held about you, and you have the right to have any inaccuracies on record about you corrected. TJX charges £10 for UK requests and will require you to prove your identity before providing any data. Send any requests for access, or queries regarding access, to the Data Protection Officer, TJX Europe, 50 Clarendon Road, Watford, WD17 1TX or email [data_protection@tjxeurope.com](mailto:data_protection@tjxeurope.com).

## Our mailing list - getting on and getting off!

When you use our website, receive an email from us, place an order or enter a competition you will get the opportunity to subscribe to our mailing list for our email newsletters - TK Maxx Email Newsletter and HomeSense Email Newsletter which keep you up to date with new and exciting products arriving in our stores and online. To subscribe, simply follow the instructions provided.

If you no longer wish to receive our emails there are several ways you can unsubscribe: 

  * Click on the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of every TK Maxx Email Newsletter and HomeSense Email Newsletter email. This will open a new page and you will need to click "Yes, unsubscribe me".
  * Contact Us and we will remove you from the list. [Click here for contact details](http://www.tkmaxx.com/page/contact).

## Do you share my information with anyone else?

We do not sell or otherwise disclose any personal information about our customers, visitors to our website or those applying for a job except as described in this Privacy and Cookies Policy or as otherwise agreed with you.

We do use third parties to perform some services on our behalf and in such cases, they may have limited access to certain personal information. In such cases, they may only use personal information strictly as instructed and never for their own purposes. Examples of when personal information you provide to us may be accessed by third parties are: 

  * When you use our website to make a purchase of goods or evouchers. Our transactional website at [www.tkmaxx.com](http://www.tkmaxx.com/) is provided by Venda. We chose Venda to provide this expertise for us because of their security certification. 
  * When you buy Store Gift cards via our website. Our store gift cards are provided by Voucher Express who will ask for the relevant details to take payment for a gift card and send it to the recipient. 
  * When you apply for a job with us online. How do we Protect your Information when you Apply for a Job?
  * When we ask you to give us independent feedback on our products and services 
  * Your name, contact details and card details upon purchase of a product online to validate this information against third party databases for purposes of fraud prevention.

TK Maxx and HomeSense are owned and operated by TJX UK, a subsidiary of The TJX Companies, Inc established in the USA. We may share the information you provide with companies who form part of our group of companies and, in certain circumstances, with our joint marketing partners. This means that the information you provide us may be transferred outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) to various countries, including the United States. This information may be subject to the laws of the countries in which it is stored or used, and those countries may have a different data protection regime than the country in which you reside. By providing us with any personal information, you consent to such transfer, processing and storage of your personal information. 

In the event that we run a promotion in conjunction with another sponsor, your personal information may be shared with such sponsors, but this will be specified at the time of collection. We do not control the use, disclosure or security of your personal information by other sponsors, so we recommend you carefully review their privacy policy. 

In addition we may disclose information: 

  * If we are required to do so by law or legal process; 
  * To law enforcement agencies; 
  * When we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation or suspected or actual illegal activity; or 
  * To selected third parties for the purpose of prevention and detection of criminal activity (including, without limitation, fraud); or 
  * If TK Maxx or HomeSense merges, sells or disposes of any part of its business or assets, which includes customer information.

## Cookie Policy

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your web-enabled device (such a computer, mobile phone, tablet etc) when you visit a website. 

### Why are they used?

They are used by websites in various ways to personalise and enhance your website experience. For example, they may be used to recognise you when you return to a website, remember your preferences, monitor your use of websites in an anonymised manner so as to improve the website’s efficiency and user-friendliness or to provide you with personalised suggestions. 

### How do we use cookies?

Where you consent to this, we use cookies on this website. For details on how to disable these cookies where you do not consent to them, see How can you refuse cookies? We have classified the cookies we use and the purposes we use them for below, according to the International Chamber of Commerce guide for cookie categories. 

**1\. Strictly Necessary**  
These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around our website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for (like shopping, baskets etc) cannot be provided. These cookies are **not** used to advertise any products or services to you.  
  
---  
  
**2\. Performance**  
These cookies collect information about how visitors use our website, for instance which pages visitors go to most often and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies do not collect personal information that identifies a visitor. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. The information collected is only used to improve how our website works. These cookies are **not** used to advertise any products or services to you.  
  
**3\. Functional**  
These cookies allow our website to remember choices you make (such as your user name, language or the region you are in) and to provide enhanced and more personal features. They can also be used to remember changes you have made to parts of our website that you can customise. The information these cookies collect is anonymised and cannot track your activity on other websites. These cookies are **not** used to advertise any products or services to you.  
  
**4\. Targeting**  
These cookies are used to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. They can also be used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. They can be placed on your device by us or by a third party with our consent. Where they are placed by us, they may be used only by us to deliver adverts more relevant to you. When placed by a third party with our consent, they may be used by that third party and other parties to deliver adverts more relevant to you and your interests. For example, where you choose to link to various social networks (such as Facebook, Twitter and Pinterest) via our website, these social network sites may place cookies on your device and use these to target advertising to you on their or other websites.   
  
The cookies we use on our website are as follows:

**1\. Strictly necessary**

Tkmaxx.com cookies

  * RFID 
  * SID 
  * newCurr 

**2\. Performance**

Tkmaxx.com cookies

  * referid 
  * httprefer 
  * newsSignupPopup

Cookies provided by third parties

Cookie  | 

Host  
  
---|---  
  
coreID6  
90208333_login

| 

data.coremetrics.eu (IBM Coremetrics)  
  
_utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmz

| 

google.com (Google)  
  
ngx_7077224  
ngx_userid  
pid2  
sid1749  
cvt56  
ngx_15737030  
JSESSIONID

| 

.gbppc.com (Merchantize)  
  
**3\. Functional**

Tkmaxx.com cookies

  * locn 
  * lang 
  * RVI 
  * Setview 
  * setViewPerPage 
  * RSI 

**4\. Targeting**

Tkmaxx.com cookies

  * Vbmprods 
  * Vbmtracker 

Cookies provided by third parties

Cookie  | 

Host

| 

Note  
  
---|---|---  
  
Guest_id  
_utma  
_utmz  
k  
Twitter_sess

| 

twitter.com (Twitter)

| 

Only placed when using Twitter functionality via tkmaxx.com.   
  
Datr  
lu

| 

facebook.com (Facebook)

| 

Only placed when using Facebook functionality via tkmaxx.com.  
  
Pinterest_sess  

| 

pinterest.com (Pinterest)

| 

Only placed when using Pinterest functionality via tkmaxx.com.  
  
CMAVID  
CoreAt  
CoreM_State  
CoreM_Ses

| 

data.coremetrics.eu (IBM Coremetrics)

|   
  
Ecos  
BIGipServerDLB02-ED70-HTTP-POOL

| 

ecustomeropinions.com

|   
  
### How can you refuse cookies?

Your browser can be adjusted to refuse cookies being set on your device or to be notified prior to such cookies being set. How this is done depends on what type of browser you use. Details of how to manage cookies are available (depending on your type of browser) at www.allaboutcookies.org or www.aboutcookies.org. According to your browser, there are instructions regarding how to delete cookies or manage them being set on your device. If the browser you use is not listed, click on the Help bar on your browser and search for information on cookies. You will find an explanation on how to delete or manage cookies. Follow the relevant instructions.   
Please note that if you refuse to consent to cookies being placed on your account, certain parts of this website may not be available to you. 

### Where can I find out more information about cookies?

Information about cookies can be found at www.allaboutcookies.org.  
The Internet Advertising Bureau provides a guide to behavioural advertising and online privacy which can be accessed at www.youronlinechoices.eu.  
The International Chamber of Commerce UK cookie guide can be found on their website at www.international-chamber.co.uk/our-expertise/digitaleconomy

## How do we protect your information when you apply for a job?

When applying for a job online with TJX you can submit your CV and other relevant personal information on our website. We will ask you to register your details by providing an email address and password. Any information you provide is maintained in a database which is managed on our behalf by a service provider in the US. They are authorised to use the information only in connection with hosting, managing and maintaining our CV database and they can process your data only in accordance with our instructions. We use the information you submit to process your application.

If you apply for a job by submitting an application form to our stores or by post, we will retain it securely for a limited period relevant to the vacancies available.

We will share your information only as requested by you or in accordance with the statements in this Privacy Policy. Information for unsuccessful candidates will be destroyed within a reasonable period once the vacancy and other suitable vacancies have been filled or the search otherwise concluded.
